ABUBAKAR SADIQ SAMBO

Abuja, Nigeria sadiqasg@gmail.com https://saslamp.github.io

SUMMARY

A graduate of Business Administration and a Software Developer with experience in building professional client products and working on projects with Government Ministries and Agencies. I work mainly with Front End technologies and have working experience with Back End / Server-side technologies and Databases.

EXPERIENCE

July 2019 - Present

PUBLIC AND PRIVATE DEVELOPMENT CENTER (PPDC)

• Software Developer (Front-end)

Responsible for building client-facing applications for in-house products and partner products.

- Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript ¡Query, NodeJs, Firebase.
- **Tools:** Github (code repository/version control), Figma Design, WhatsApp (team communications).

March 2019 – April 2019

INTELLECTUAL APPS LTD.

Web Developer - Contract

Collaborated in building a taxation app.

- **Technologies**: HTML, CSS, jQuery, Java.
- **Tools:** Bitbucket (code repository/version control) and Slack (team communications).

November 2018 – January 2019

Unicef – ministry of health

- CMAM Data Monitor:
- Monitor data of selected facilities, record stock and Interview the head of each OTP facility
 on how they handle cases. Also, where needed, offer a guide on best practices and how to
 properly record data of malnutrition cases.

June 2018 – October 2018

TANN TECHNOLOGIES

Frontend Developer.

Responsible for designing mock-ups and building the client-facing implementation.

- **Technologies**: Javascript Angular(6)
- **Tools:** Figma Design, Bitbucket (code repository/version control) and Slack (team communications).

April 2018 – June 2018

Hotels.ng

• Remote Software Developer Intern

Collaborated with UI designers and Backend developers, in teams, to carry out tasks following project specifications.

- **Technologies**: HTML, CSS, PHP, Bootstrap.
- Tools: Slack, Github, Teamviewer, Pivotal Tracker.

June 2015 – May 2016

DIALOGUE COMPUTER INSTITUTE, KADUNA

• Administrative Assistant – Registrar's Office (NYSC PPA)

EDUCATION

In-Progress (Dec 2021)

EDX | HARVARDX ONLINE CS50

Web programming with Python and Javascript

Awarded 2020

UDEMY

• Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

Awarded 2019

OPENCLASSROOMS

• Certificates in Software Engineering (HTML, React, Node, and Express)

Awarded 2018

ANDELA LEARNING COMMUNITY WITH MICROSOFT

• Computer Programming – Frontend Web Developer Course

Awarded 2016

NIGERIAN INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT (CHARTERED)

Proficiency Certificate in Management

Awarded 2015

UNIVERSITY OF ABUJA, FCT

B.Sc. Business Administration

Final Year Research Project: The role of small and medium-scale enterprises in the economic development of Nigeria.

Awarded 2008

AIR FORCE COMPREHENSIVE SCHOOL UYO, AKWA IBOM

Senior Secondary School Certificate

Awarded 2002

FTMC NURSERY AND PRIMARY SCHOOL FESTAC, LAGOS

Primary School Leaving Certificate

OTHER CERTIFICATIONS

- Go Full-stack with Node.js, Express, and MongoDB Openclassrooms.
- Frontend Web Developer Course ALC with Microsoft.
- Certificate of Computer Science OAU Consultancy Services Center, Suleja.

LANGUAGES

- Proficient in English and Hausa languages.
- Limited proficiency in Yoruba and Arabic.
- Basic Deutsche (Learning).

INTERESTS

• Documentaries on Astronomy, Travelling, Chess, Football, Swimming and Horse-riding.